<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
<title type="text"></title>
<generator uri="https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll">Jekyll</generator>
<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" />
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000" />
<updated>2016-09-21T17:11:00+02:00</updated>
<id>http://localhost:4000/</id>
<author>
  <name>António Domingues</name>
  <uri>http://localhost:4000/</uri>
  <email>amjdomingues@gmail</email>
</author>


  

<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Salmon and spinach in a bed of celeriac]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/blog/Salmon-Spinach-and-egg/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/blog/Salmon-Spinach-and-egg</id>
  <published>2016-09-20T21:00:02+02:00</published>
  <updated>2016-09-20T21:00:02+02:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>António Domingues</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>amjdomingues@gmail</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;This recipe started as a recommendation from my sister, after she tried a recipe seen on TV. It used quiuetiessencial Portuguese ingredients like cod, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alheira&quot;&gt;Alheira&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Broa&quot;&gt;Broa&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rapini&quot;&gt;Grelos&lt;/a&gt;. I did try it once with the proper ingredients, but I don’t always the time to go the Portuguese grocery store. So through and iterative process of bastardization, Grelos became spinach, Cod is now salmon, and Alheira/Broa are nowhere to be seen and became celeriac.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This new recipe is now something that most people can do with ingredients that are readily available, looks goods and wonderfully fresh and different. Do not fear the celeriac! It is wonderful vegetable, very versatile whose flavor has a hint of sweetness and is a (very) watered down version of the more pungent celery stalks. The eggs combines wonderfully with the salmon and makes adds some color to it - as we say “os olhos também comem” (~ eyes also eat).  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/9519660/foodforthepeople/img/SpinachAndSalmon.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Tuna salad for the win&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The results is dish full of flavor with citrus notes without being overpowering. As it is custom in Food For the People, it was prepared with some frozen ingredients (Salmon and Spinach) which makes it relatively easy to prepare when there is no time to do some fresh grocery shopping after work. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;variations&quot;&gt;Variations&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.joseavillez.pt/jdownloads/Receitas/Receitas_S1/receita_p2_15jun_lascas_bacalhau.pdf&quot;&gt;original recipe&lt;/a&gt; which I will translate one of these days. Also, thyme instead of rosemary. For the fish, I should try haddock one of these days. Take the fish away and you will have a vegetarian dish. &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chard&quot;&gt;Swiss Chard&lt;/a&gt; could also replace the spinach and it combines very well with orange.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;inspiration&quot;&gt;Inspiration&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The inspiring recipe can be found &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.joseavillez.pt/jdownloads/Receitas/Receitas_S1/receita_p2_15jun_lascas_bacalhau.pdf&quot;&gt;here (Portuguese)&lt;/a&gt; and it is a creation of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.joseavillez.pt&quot;&gt;Chef José Avillez&lt;/a&gt;. That said, the recipe has changed so much that is bares little resemblance with the original.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For celeriac I stole the recipe from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jamieoliver.com/recipes/vegetables-recipes/simple-as-that-celeriac/&quot;&gt;Jamie Oliver&lt;/a&gt; and modified it a little.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Servings: 2&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Prep Time:  15 mins&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cook Time:  35 mins&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Total Time: 50 mins&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Celeriac: 1, roughly cubbed in 0.5-1 cm pieces&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Salmon fillet: 2, aprox. 250 grams&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Spinach, 500 grams&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Eggs: 2&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lemon: 1, zest&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Orange: 1, juice&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rosemary leaves, 1 tablespoon, chopped&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Olive oil: 3 tablespoons, extra to brush&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Garlic clove: 1, sliced&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sea salt: to taste&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Black Pepper: to taste&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Top the celeriac, peel it with a knife removing the rough bits, and cut into 1 cm cubes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Put a casserole-type pan on a medium-high heat and add 2 tablespoons of olive oil. Once warm, add the celeriac cubes, thyme leaves and lemon zest. Add some salt, mix it all together, and turn the heat down to medium. Cover and cook for 20 to 25 minutes, or until tender. Mix it every know and then.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Preheat oven to 220ºc. Brush the Salmon fillets with olive oil, and season with salt and pepper. Pop in in the oven for about 15 minutes or until it starts tearing apart when you put a fork to it. Once done, flake it and put it aside.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Once the celeric is done (it’s soft and slightly brown), remove it from the pan, add some olive oil if needed and sauté the spinach with the garlic in the same pan. As it wilts, add the salmon, orange juice and mix it all together at low eat.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fry the eggs sunny side up in a thin layer of olive oil. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;On a deep plate or bowl, layer the celeriac, the salmon spinach mix, and top it off with the egg.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Enjoy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/blog/Salmon-Spinach-and-egg/&quot;&gt;Salmon and spinach in a bed of celeriac&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by António Domingues at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on September 20, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


  

<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Liver and Chicken hearts stew with cabbage and parsnip chips]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/blog/Liver-and-Chicken-hearts-stew/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/blog/Liver-and-Chicken-hearts-stew</id>
  <published>2016-09-16T18:12:02+02:00</published>
  <updated>2016-09-16T18:12:02+02:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>António Domingues</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>amjdomingues@gmail</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;When the sun starts setting early, the body starts aching for some more substantial food, and salads no long have an appeal. it is time for an earthy dish, with one of the most nutritious, flavorsome, and yet vilified, organ meats: liver. It is also a very cheap meat that and cooks extremely fast. To add to the Autumnal feel of this dish, there is also cabbage and parsnip. All in all a very healthy and flavorsome dish. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;variations&quot;&gt;Variations&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of the hearts and liver, you can use just one of those, or replace them with giblets. Additionally, spicy it up with more piri-piri and serve it as a snack with a beer (or two) and friends. This variation is very popular in Portugal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The parsnip fries will go well with other dishes, specially roasts. You can also experiment with other spices or herbs, for instance Rosemary, instead of the paprika.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And how to pick the best &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chorizo&quot;&gt;Chouriço&lt;/a&gt; you ask? Actually, for this dish the &lt;em&gt;best&lt;/em&gt; chouriço is not what you are looking for. The best one is mostly meat, and very little fat, which excellent as a &lt;em&gt;petisco&lt;/em&gt; (appetizer or &lt;em&gt;Tapas&lt;/em&gt;). For this dish however, you want one with fast which will release the nice spices into the sauce. We call it “Chouriço corrente”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;inspiration&quot;&gt;Inspiration&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the stew the starting point was a classical &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.saborintenso.com/f21/petisco-moelas-323/&quot;&gt;Portuguese giblets snack&lt;/a&gt; which I replaced with liver and hearths because my SO is not fond of giblets. The cabbage was a serendipitous experiment one day that there was some left over in the fridge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are plenty of parsnip fries in the interwebs, but &lt;a href=&quot;http://ahouseinthehills.com/2014/02/04/paprika-parsnip-fries/&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; is one of the simplest ones. My version is pretty much the same - without the extra sauce - and adjusted for my oven.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Servings: 4&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Prep Time:  30 mins&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cook Time:  40 mins&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Total Time: 70 mins&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Stew&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;chiken hearts and livers: 1000 g, frozen&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Savoy cabbage: half, diced&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Onion: 1, chopped&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Garlic: 2, chopped&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Butter: 2 tablespoon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;White wine: 3 dl, or lager/IPA/bitter beer&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Water: 2 dl&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Chouriço: 70 grams, cubbed in small chunks&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tomato paste: 6 tablespoons&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bay leaves: 3 &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Piri-piri: to taste, can be replaced with dried chilies&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Salt: to taste, can be replaced with dried chilies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Parsnip chips&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Parsnips: 6, about 500 grams&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Olive oil: 1 tablespoon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Paprika: to taste, about a teaspoon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sea salt: to taste&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Parsnip fries&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Preheat oven to 190ºc.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Peel the parsnips - a potato peeler will do - chop the tops off, and cut in fries.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mix the parsnips with the olive oil, paprika and salt, and lay in a roasting tin covered with baking paper. Roast for 25 minutes, turn them and roast for another 10 minutes. Mind you times may vary depending on your oven. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Red Curi Squash mash&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Thaw the the liver and hearts, wash with cold water, remove extra fat, dry with kitchen paper and cut the livers in half.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In a pot, fry the livers in butter for about 5 minutes in medium heat until they are half-done. They will finish cooking later in the stew. Removed them from the pot and set aside.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If needed add some more butter to the pan, and gently fry onion and garlic. Also add the bay leaves.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;After about 5 minutes, or when the onion is translucent, add the chouriço frying it for a little bit to release some of the spices and fat, and then hearts mixing it all together. Add some salt and the chilies/piri-piri, cover the pot and fry for 5 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Throw in the tomato paste, wine and water, mix it all up, cook for another 10 minutes and then add the cabbage. In the closed pot the cabbage will wilt during the cooking. Let it cook for about 15 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add the livers, mix it all up so it can gain extra flavor from the sauce and cook for another 5 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/blog/Liver-and-Chicken-hearts-stew/&quot;&gt;Liver and Chicken hearts stew with cabbage and parsnip chips&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by António Domingues at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on September 16, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


  

<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tahini and tuna salad]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/blog/Tahini-and-tuna-salad/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/blog/Tahini-and-tuna-salad</id>
  <published>2016-09-15T20:00:02+02:00</published>
  <updated>2016-09-15T20:00:02+02:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>António Domingues</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>amjdomingues@gmail</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;Summer is now almost over, but it is still warm enough for salads. And a salad does not need to be a sad affair, even if the ingredients are run of the mill, as I have been discovering. This one has Tuna in it to remind me of the Ocean, which I dearly miss, and tahini (sesame paste) to make me feel fancy. The halloumi is there to bulk it up and make it a proper main dish. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/9519660/foodforthepeople/img/TunaTahiniSalad.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Tuna salad for the win&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fancy ingredients, tahini and halloumi, can be found in large supermarkets, health food stores or Turkish/Middle Eastern stores, and they keep for long, specially the tahini, so no need to go every week to a store on the other side of town. The green used for the salad can be whatever you have at hand and can be eaten raw - any variety of lettuce, watercress, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Valerianella&quot;&gt;Valerianella&lt;/a&gt;, or a mix of all of these will do. The first time I have seen Valerianella was in Germany, so I am not sure about the availability in other countries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I noticed that depending on the brand, tahini can be more or less fatty and I was suspicious that some of it might be of lower quality. So, I asked a colleague that has a middle eastern background if there was any way to choose “the best” tahini and apparently having a layer of fat at the top of the jar is normal and expected. Unless it is too much, let’s say 1/4 of the volume, it actually indicates a good quality tahini. One thing to bear in mind is one should homogenize the tahini - for instance with a spoon - before taking it from the jar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for the halloumi, don’t fret if you can’t find “real” halloumi - any grill cheese with do, and I tend to buy the cheap ones pre-marinated with chili. And if you don’t have it or are not that hungry, no problem, the salad will work without it as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whilst you could use black pepper to season this dish, I strongly recommend white pepper which goes extremely well with some fish dishes.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;source&quot;&gt;Source&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inspiration from a &lt;a href=&quot;http://stupideasypaleo.com/2015/01/30/paleo-lemon-tahini-tuna-salad-recipe/&quot;&gt;paleo website&lt;/a&gt;, modified to include some extra  ingredients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Servings: 2&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Prep Time:  20 mins&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cook Time:  10 mins&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Total Time:  30 mins&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tuna: 140g, canned in water&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Salad greens: 2-3 cups, for instance half a lettuce.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cherry tomatoes: a handful&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;lemon juice: 2-3 tablespoons, or 1 lemon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Garlic: 1 clove, pressed&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;White pepper: 1 teaspoon, or to taste&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sea salt: to taste&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Olive oil: 2 tablespoons&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wash the salad and the tomatoes. Shred the salad and halve or quarter the tomatoes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lay the salad on large plates, dot with the tomatoes, drizzle the olive oil, and add a bit of salt.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Brush slightly the halloumi with olive oil and grill it in a grill pan with medium heat.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;While the halloumi is grilling, take a bowl and mix the tahini, lemon juice, garlic, tuna (without the water), and white pepper. If the mixture is too thick add some drops of water, but remember it should have the consistency of a paste. Spoon it into the middle of the plates.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Finish off by cutting the grilled halloumi in small pieces and dotting the salad with it. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;


    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/blog/Tahini-and-tuna-salad/&quot;&gt;Tahini and tuna salad&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by António Domingues at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on September 15, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


  

<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Feta cheesecake]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/blog/Feta-cheesecake/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/blog/Feta-cheesecake</id>
  <published>2016-09-09T17:00:02+02:00</published>
  <updated>2016-09-09T17:00:02+02:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>António Domingues</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>amjdomingues@gmail</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;I follow the food articles on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/&quot;&gt;The Guardian&lt;/a&gt; in search of inspiration for when I need something different. Most of the times the recipes are not People-friendly and require way too many odd (expensive) ingredients or are a full time job. There however times when something hits the sweet spot (pun intended) and this &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2016/sep/03/feta-cheese-cheesecake-filo-frittata-recipe-swap&quot;&gt;cheesecake with Feta&lt;/a&gt; is a case in point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For this recipe I had to do very few minor changes, mostly due to the fact that I don’t own a 20 cm cake form, but rather a 25 cm, so the ingredients for the filling were scaled up by a 1/3, with one exception: sugar. The original recipe is quite generous with the sugar, 160g, whereas half of that is enough for me. My recommendation is that, if following the original recipe, you start with half of the sugar, and taste the filling adjusting if needed, before adding it to the crust. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another change, this time by complete accident but turned out to add even more flavor, was that I added the lemon juice to the filling by accident - it should have been only the zest. This mistake paid off though. Also, I did not have black sesame seeds (who does?) so I used normal sesame seeds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since the amount of filling was increased in my version, time in the oven was also extended by about 5-10 minutes. Check the cake after 40 minutes and  if not slightly brown on the top, extend the time as needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;things-to-try&quot;&gt;Things to try&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;replace sugar with honey&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;replace digestive biscuits crust with an almond flour based one&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/9519660/foodforthepeople/img/FetaCheesecake.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A lovely dessert can be prepared in a few minutes.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;source&quot;&gt;Source&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All credits go to &lt;a href=&quot;https://witness.theguardian.com/user/borrowedbread&quot;&gt;Faye Cooke&lt;/a&gt; and The Guardian.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So here are my changes to the recipe, though if you stick to the original you won’t go wrong. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Servings: 8-10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Prep Time:  30 mins&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cooking Time:  45 mins&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Total Time:  75 mins&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Digestive biscuits: 150g, crushed&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Salt: a pinch &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sesame seeds: 1 1/2 tablespoon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Butter: 50 grams, melted&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Feta: 300 grams&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cream cheese: 400 grams&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Eggs: 3&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Zest of 1 lemon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Caster sugar: 80 grams&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Peaches: 2&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Raspberries: 100 grams, frozen &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lemon juice: 2 tablespoons&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Honey: 1 tablespoons&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Unsalted butter: 20g &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Thyme: 1 sprig, leaves picked&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Line a 20cm springform cake tin with greaseproof paper. Put the biscuit crumbs into a bowl with the salt and sesame seeds and mix in the melted butter until well combined. Press the mixture into the bottom of the cake tin, evening out with the back of a spoon, and put in the fridge while you prepare the filling.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Preheat the oven to 180C/350F/gas mark 4. In a mixing bowl, break down the feta using a fork. Whisk in the cream cheese, eggs, lemon zest, one tablespoon of lemon juice and the sugar. Put the tin on a baking sheet, pour the filling on to the crust and give it a tap to even it out. Bake in the middle of the oven for 40 minutes, or until almost set.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Meanwhile, dice the peaches and put the pieces in a roasting tray with the raspberries, lemon juice and the honey. Flake over the unsalted butter, cover with foil and set aside. When the cheesecake has 15 minutes left, put the roasting tin on the bottom shelf of the oven.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Remove the cheesecake and fruit from the oven. Let them cool slightly. Carefully transfer the cheesecake to a plate. Lift the fruit from its juice and spoon on top of the cheesecake. Pour over 1 tbsp the juice, then chill the rest.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Scatter over the thyme leaves. Serve with the reserved juice from the fruits.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;


    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/blog/Feta-cheesecake/&quot;&gt;Feta cheesecake&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by António Domingues at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on September 09, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


  

<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Refreshing Mallorca salad]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/blog/Mallorca-salad/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/blog/Mallorca-salad</id>
  <published>2016-09-06T19:11:02+02:00</published>
  <updated>2016-09-06T19:11:02+02:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>António Domingues</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>amjdomingues@gmail</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;What I like about this salad its the freshness that comes from the peaches added to the tanginess of the white wine vinegar. It is also very colorful and a treat to the eyes. Even though it can be eaten by itself in a warm summer evening, it is perfect as a side in a BBQ. Vegetarian friendly, though not in the picture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/9519660/foodforthepeople/img/MallorcaSalad.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Sometimes a salad comes with little sausages.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;source&quot;&gt;Source&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This recipe was nicked from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.randomhouse.de/Buch/Kochbuch/Tim-Maelzer/Mosaik-Verlag/e241466.rhd&quot;&gt;this recipe book&lt;/a&gt;, so all credits go to Tim Mälzer (a famous TV chef in Germany). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;variations&quot;&gt;Variations&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;As per usual, once I messed up the grocery shopping, so instead of the tomatoes I got a cucumber, and instead of the green pepper I got a red. Went ahead and made the salad with these ingredients and it worked. I still prefer the tomatoes for this salad though. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Servings: 2 as a main dish or 3-4 as a side&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Prep Time:  20 minutes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rest Time: 10 minutes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Total Time:  30 minutes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Feta cheese: 150 grams&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Onions: 1&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Green bell pepper: 1&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Yellow bell pepper: 1&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tomatoes: 4&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Peaches: 2&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Olive oil: 6 tablespoons&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;White wine vinegar: 3-4 tablespoons&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Black pepper: to taste&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sea salt: to taste&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sugar: a pinch&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Peel the onion, de-seed the bell peppers and the tomatoes, and remove the core from the peaches. Cut everything, including the Feta in small pieces.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In a bowl, Mix the onion, peaches, peppers and tomatoes with the olive oil, vinegar, salt, black pepper and sugar. Let it marinate for 10 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Check the salad for taste and add the Feta.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Serve.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;


    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/blog/Mallorca-salad/&quot;&gt;Refreshing Mallorca salad&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by António Domingues at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on September 06, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


  

<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Duck breast with Pumpkin mash]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/blog/Duck-with-red-curi-squash-mash/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/blog/Duck-with-red-curi-squash-mash</id>
  <published>2016-09-03T20:15:02+02:00</published>
  <updated>2016-09-03T20:15:02+02:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>António Domingues</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>amjdomingues@gmail</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;Sometimes one wants to eat something nice and different, without having too much trouble or spending too much money. Or we want to impress guests. This one such recipe. The Duck screams &lt;em&gt;Vive la France&lt;/em&gt; and the pumpkin mash is seasonal, tasty and colorful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the Pumpkin mash I took some inspiration from this BBC Good Food recipe, but replaced the Butternut Squash with Red Curi squash, also know as &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Red_kuri_squash&quot;&gt;Hokkaido amongst other names&lt;/a&gt;. I did this because:
1. that was the pumpkin available in the market, and 
2. this variety does not to be peeled saving a lot of time and effort.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other pumpkins could also be used, so check what your supermarket has on offer. Also, if Dolcelate is not available use Gorgonzola or other Blue Cheese. Try and choose a mild one unless you like pungent cheese flavors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/9519660/foodforthepeople/img/PumkinMashAndDuck.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Some fancy stuff&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;variations&quot;&gt;Variations&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the gravy you can use pretty much any fruit compote, or even a splash of orange juice. I did it before and it works. Almost anything fruity will go nicely with duck, so just experiment with whatever you have lying around in the kitchen. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Servings: 4&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Prep Time:  30 mins&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cook Time:  40 mins&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Total Time: 70 mins&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Red Curi Squash mash&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dolcelatte cheese: 100 g&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Red Curi squash: One medium/Large&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Olive oil, 1 tablespoon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Black pepper: to taste, if available use pepper with citrus flavor&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sea salt: to taste&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fresh chives, 1 tablespoon, to garnish optional &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pan-fried duck&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Duck breasts: 2, about 225g each&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Black pepper: to taste, if available use pepper with citrus flavor&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sea salt: to taste&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Port wine: 10 mL&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cornflour: 1 teaspoon of &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cranberry jam: 2 tablespoons, optional&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Red Curi Squash mash&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wash the squash, remove the seeds, and cut in large chunks.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Boil the pieces of squash in water with a little salt until tender - 15 to 20 minutes should do it.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Place the cheese, oil and cooked butternut into a bowl. Season with salt and freshly ground black pepper, then mash together.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To serve spoon the mash onto the middle of a serving plate and sprinkle over the chopped chives.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pan-fried duck&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;While the pumpkin is cooking, lightly score the skins of the duck breasts with a sharp knife. Rub the the duck breasts with salt and pepper and leave to stand for about 10 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Lay the duck breasts, skin side down, in a dry heavy-based large frying pan and gradually turn up the heat. Fry for five to 10 minutes, until most of the fat has rendered and the skin is golden brown.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Turn the duck breasts over and lightly brown the other side for a couple of minutes, or until they feel slightly springy when pressed. Remove from the pan and leave to rest in a warm place while you make the sauce. Note: if the duck breasts are thick and you prefer to have it well done, start the over at 180ºC, transfer the meat to a baking tray and roast for 5-10 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For the sauce, pour off excess fat from the frying pan and place over a high heat. Pour in the port, stirring to deglaze, and let bubble for a minute. Add the cranberry jam and reduce the heat. Mix the cornflour with a splash of cold water to dissolve, and add it to the pan mixing well. Let it bubble until the liquid has the desired consistency. If it gets too thick, add a splash of water and mix.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Add any juices from the resting duck. Taste and adjust the seasoning and add some jam or orange juice if desired. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Slice the duck breasts on the diagonal and fan them out on warmed serving plates. Spoon the sauce around the duck and serve with the mashed celery root.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;


    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/blog/Duck-with-red-curi-squash-mash/&quot;&gt;Duck breast with Pumpkin mash&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by António Domingues at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on September 03, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


  

<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tomato and salmon salad]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/blog/Tomato-and-salmon-salad/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/blog/Tomato-and-salmon-salad</id>
  <published>2016-08-22T22:15:02+02:00</published>
  <updated>2016-08-22T22:15:02+02:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>António Domingues</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>amjdomingues@gmail</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;Salad is a staple for those warm summer nights. Mots of the time, we stick to leafy green salads, but once in a while is good to have something different, specially something with fish. While in Portugal I copied a few recipes from magazines lying around my mum’s kitchen, and one of them was for a salad with grilled tuna, avocado and tomatoes. Brilliant. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the recipe at hand, I went grocery shopping, and when back at home things started going south. Guess what: the avocado was over-ripe - actually black inside - so this had to be excluded. There was no tuna in our freezer but salmon is a good replacement. Also, instead of the coriander from the original recipe, there was some parsley left-over that needed eating. The egg was not in the original recipe, but I find the combination of salmon and egg a very good one. So there. In end it turned to be a very tasty summery salad even though a completely different one from the original.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;source&quot;&gt;Source&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inspiration from a recipe published in a magazine of a large Portuguese supermarket chain, Continente. If you can read Portuguese, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://chef.continente.pt/&quot;&gt;sister website&lt;/a&gt; has plenty of good recipes with a very good search function.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Servings: 2&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Prep Time:  10 mins&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cook Time:  20 mins&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Total Time:  30 mins&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;salmon fillets: 2 pieces&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;eggs: 2 pieces&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cherry tomatoes: 300 grams&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Red onion: 1 piece&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Parsley: a handful&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Black pepper: to taste&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sea salt: to taste&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Olive oil: 3 tablespoons, extra to brush the salmon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lime juice: 2 tablespoons, or a lime&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pre-heat the oven at 190ºc.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Brush salmon fillets with olive oil and season with salt.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Oven-grill the salmon for 15-20 min.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;While the Salmon is grilling, halve the tomatoes, thinly slice the onion,  and roughly chop the parley. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add a spoon of olive oil to a frying pan, or whatever amount is needed to coat the pan, and fry the eggs sunny side up.  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In a small bowl, stir together the tomatoes, onions, parsley, olive oil, lime juice, and season with salt and pepper.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Serve in a plate with the vegetables on a side, and the egg on top of the salmon.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;


    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/blog/Tomato-and-salmon-salad/&quot;&gt;Tomato and salmon salad&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by António Domingues at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on August 22, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


  

<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Raffaello copycat]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/blog/Mock-Raffaello/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/blog/Mock-Raffaello</id>
  <published>2016-08-22T18:11:02+02:00</published>
  <updated>2016-08-22T18:11:02+02:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>António Domingues</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>amjdomingues@gmail</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;I like desserts with coconut or nuts, thus when a colleague told me about this Low-Carb version of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Raffaello_(confection)&quot;&gt;Raffaello pralines&lt;/a&gt; I just had to try it. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Raffaello are a commercially available sweet that happens to have both coconut and almonds, and but for the excessive sweetness (for my taste anyway) it is quite good actually. The recipe does not quite replicate the sweet - I failed to form proper pralines with the proper shape - but makes a very &lt;em&gt;coconutty&lt;/em&gt;, easy to prepare dessert. It is made with pre-packaged ingredients, most of which might already be in one’s pantry - except maybe for the almond meal or coconut flour - so something to prepare in a hurry when guests come unannounced. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/9519660/foodforthepeople/img/Raffaello.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A lovely dessert can be prepared in a few minutes.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few notes on the ingredients: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Quark_(dairy_product)&quot;&gt;quark&lt;/a&gt; is an dairy product common in central Europe, and it is very versatile and tasty. It is something between a full fat Yogurt and cottage cheese. I use it very often as dessert with Apple mousse (and cinnamon). If you can’t get your hands to it, use another fresh cheese. Check the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Quark_(dairy_product)&quot;&gt;wiki&lt;/a&gt; article for names and alternatives in other languages/countries.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The almond flour is used to increase the consistency of the mixture and can be replaced by other nut flours or coconut flour.  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Honey can be replaced with plain sugar. I prefer honey.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Servings: 4&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Prep Time:  20 mins&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rest Time:  30 mins&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Total Time:  50 mins&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Quark (10% fat): 150 grams&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Coconut milk: 170 ml&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Shredded coconut: 2-3 tablespoons&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Honey: 1 tablespoon, or to taste&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Almond flour: 1-2 tablespoons, optional&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ground hazelnuts: 1-2 tablespoons, to add on top&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In a bowl mix all the ingredients, except the ground hazelnuts, until they have a nice smooth consistency. This can be done with a spoon, or whisker or a KitchenAid style mixer.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Leave it for at least 20 minutes in the fridge to cool off and acquire consistency.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Serve in small dessert bowls and dot with the ground hazelnuts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;


    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/blog/Mock-Raffaello/&quot;&gt;A Raffaello copycat&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by António Domingues at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on August 22, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


  

<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[The start]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/articles/the-start/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/articles/the-start</id>
  <published>2016-08-15T00:00:00+02:00</published>
  <updated>2016-08-15T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name></name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h3 id=&quot;food&quot;&gt;Food&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We all love food… we’ll I do, and luckily for you I also like to share recipes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;cooking--science--coding&quot;&gt;Cooking ~ Science ~ Coding&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cooking, like science and coding involves several iterations, failed experiments, and “this could be improved”. So this is the place where modifications to recipes will be recorded so that our future selfs and others can use them. This being GitHub, it also means that others can see what went wrong and improve on it. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;authors-and-contributors&quot;&gt;Authors and Contributors&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It will be mostly done by me, @adomingues, with the help of my partner in crime, AF, which does not have a GitHub account. Yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The recipes are sourced from a few cookbooks, the internet and friends/family. Whenever possible the source will be clearly stated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;contact&quot;&gt;Contact&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tips, hints, and cookies to my &lt;a href=&quot;amjdomingues@gmail.com&quot;&gt;inbox&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;resources-used-to-create-the-blog&quot;&gt;Resources used to create the blog&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This &lt;a href=&quot;https://help.github.com/articles/creating-project-pages-manually/&quot;&gt;tutorial&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://mmistakes.github.io/so-simple-theme/theme-setup/&quot;&gt;Theme&lt;/a&gt;, with credits to Michael Rose.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/articles/the-start/&quot;&gt;The start&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by António Domingues at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on August 15, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>

</feed>