<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
<title type="text"></title>
<generator uri="https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll">Jekyll</generator>
<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" />
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000" />
<updated>2020-04-13T21:51:09+02:00</updated>
<id>http://localhost:4000/</id>
<author>
  <name>António Domingues</name>
  <uri>http://localhost:4000/</uri>
  <email>amjdomingues@gmail</email>
</author>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Easter South Portuguese Lamb]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/blog/Portuguese-Egg-and-Citrus-Pudding/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/blog/Portuguese-Egg-and-Citrus-Pudding</id>
  <published>2020-04-12T23:24:02+02:00</published>
  <updated>2020-04-12T23:24:02+02:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>António Domingues</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>amjdomingues@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;In parts of Portugal it is a tradition to eat lamb, or goat, in Easter Sunday. this is a recipe from the Southern Portugal, Alentejo, with my own twist. It requires very little cooking know-how and very few ingredients. It does require to be marinated in advance for the full flavor experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taste: amazing!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/images/img/Easter_lamb_III.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Intense&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;replacements&quot;&gt;Replacements&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of piri-piri sauce, use sweet paprika powder, about a tablespoon. This will not add as much heat to the dish, so you can also add a little cayenne pepper for that.
I served it with sliced oranges, and it tasted good, but it is not a requirement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;tip&quot;&gt;Tip&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your supermarket doesn’t have Lamb, look for an Halal butcher, or a Indian / Arab / Turkish supermarket.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;source&quot;&gt;Source&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used &lt;a href=&quot;https://amariaeduarda.blogs.sapo.pt/borrego-assado-no-forno-pascoa-2018-1-20182&quot;&gt;this recipe&lt;/a&gt; as a starting point, but added my own twist, and oven times and temperature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Servings: 6&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Prep Time: 20 mins&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Marinating time: 8 hours&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cooking Time: 2 hours&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Total Time:  2 hours and 30 mins&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Leg of lamb: 2 kgs, cut in pieces&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;White wine, dry: 1 liter (at least)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Onions: 2, cut in half and then diced&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Garlic: 6 cloves, chopped&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;potatoes: 6 medium, 1-2 cm cubes or wedges&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;carrots: 6, 1-2 cm cubes or wedges&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;green beans: 200 grams&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rosemary: 2 sprigs&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Parsley: 2 stalks&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bay leaves: 2&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lemon juice: 1 tbsp&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Olive oil, 3 tbsp&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sea salt: to taste&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Piri-piri: to taste, about 1 tbsp&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;At the bottom of an oven-proof, ideally ceramic, make a layer with the onions, garlic and bay leaves. Drizzle with the olive oil. 
&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/images/img/Easter_lamb_I.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Step 1&quot; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lay on top of the onions the lamb pieces, scatter the salt and piri-piri (or paprika).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In between the pieces of lamb, tuck in the rosemary and parsley&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pour the wine until all the meat is nearly covered, and finally pour the lemon juice.
&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/images/img/Easter_lamb_II.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Step 2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cover and let it rest for several hours, ideally overnight, in the fridge.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Heat the oven to 175º c, and cook for 2 hours. You can check if the meat is done after one and half hours.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;While the meat is in the oven, peel and cut the potatoes and carrots, put them in a roasting tin. Pour over a small glass of white wine and salt to taste (a crushed garlic or two will also do wonders).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Once the meat has been in the oven for one hour, add the tray with vegetables to the oven and cook for 45 minutes to one hour (the wedges will take longer).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Once the meat is nearly done, boil the green beens for 5-10 minutes until tender but not overdone.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Enjoy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/blog/Portuguese-Egg-and-Citrus-Pudding/&quot;&gt;Easter South Portuguese Lamb&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by António Domingues at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on April 12, 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Portuguese egg and citrus pudding]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/blog/Portuguese-Egg-and-Citrus-Pudding/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/blog/Portuguese-Egg-and-Citrus-Pudding</id>
  <published>2019-02-10T11:40:02+01:00</published>
  <updated>2019-02-10T11:40:02+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>António Domingues</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>amjdomingues@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/images/img/EggPudding.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Portuguese sSyle Pudding &quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Egg pudding is a classic Portuguese dessert, a mainstay in pretty much every middle / working class Portuguese Restaurant. It is also found in a lot of homes for special occasions. In fact, every time this dessert makes an appearance is a special occasion in and of itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This particular recipe was handed down to me by my mom, and it just sweet enough but also feels fresh (courtesy) of the citrus flavor with help to lighten the richness of the eggs. It contains very few ingredients (5!) that you will probably have lying around the house at any point in time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;tips-and-tricks&quot;&gt;Tips and tricks&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.de/search?biw=1435&amp;amp;bih=825&amp;amp;tbm=isch&amp;amp;sa=1&amp;amp;ei=KPdfXOT8BoT3kwX8socY&amp;amp;q=ring+shapped+baking+tin&amp;amp;oq=ring+shapped+baking+tin&amp;amp;gs_l=img.3...10327.12668..13014...0.0..1.313.1260.9j2j0j1......0....1..gws-wiz-img.......0i7i30j0.IO0_c830cDk&quot;&gt;ring shaped baking tin&lt;/a&gt; (baking tin with a hole in the middle) if at all possible. I can’t promise it will work without it but it might.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To save some time and headache get some premade caramelized sugar. It should contain two ingredients only: sugar and water. If it contains anything else, it’s not what you want. Any local Portuguese / Spanish store will have it. If you want o makeit yourselves, then follow one of the many available instructions only, for instance &lt;a href=&quot;http://whatchaucooking.blogspot.com/2010/01/egg-pudding-portuguese-flan.html&quot;&gt;this one&lt;/a&gt; written in English, or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZpuIiRca-5A&quot;&gt;this video&lt;/a&gt; in Portuguese.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The main trick is to find the right stove setting for the water bath. Too high and it will look like an omelet, too low and it will take double the time to cook. In doubt start with a lower setting and adjust after the first 45 minutes if needed.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Very important is to get a very good lemon and orange otherwise the flavor will be a bit flat. That said, you can use juice from the pack in a pinch.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Replacing orange juice with kumquat juice works beautifully.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This pudding is similar to a Flan, but better.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;source&quot;&gt;Source&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Me mum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Servings: 8&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Prep Time:  20-30 mins&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cooking Time:  45 mins&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Total Time:  65-75 mins&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pudding&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sugar: 200 grams&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Eggs: 6&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Milk: 500 ml (warm but not boiling)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lemon zest from 1 lemon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Orange juice: 1 table spoon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caramelized sugar (optional)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sugar: 150 grams&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Water: 150 ml&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pudding&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;With an hand mixer (or KitchenAid), mix the eggs with the sugar, lemon zest and orange juice. Keep mixing and slowly drip the warm milk.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Spread the caramel all over the inside of the baking it to coat it generously. Having extra caramel on the bottom is not a problem, in fact you want that. Pour the egg mixture in the tin, put the lid on top and cook in a water bath (covering 3/4 of the backing tin) at medium low temperature (4/10 on my induction stove) for 45 min.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Check if is cooked by sticking a spaghetti or a toothpick pick in the pudding. If it isn’t just cook longer in intervals of 15-30 min to avoid overcooking.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Let it cool in the fridge for a few hours before flipping over plate. You might need to bang (gently) the tin a few times before it comes out.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Enjoy!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caramelized sugar&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In the pudding baking tin add the sugar and water, and turn up the heating to boil it.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When it starts getting some color, mix with a spoon and let it boil gently until it has a dark brown caramel color (not too dark otherwise it will burn). Take it out of the heat and put aside.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/blog/Portuguese-Egg-and-Citrus-Pudding/&quot;&gt;Portuguese egg and citrus pudding&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by António Domingues at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on February 10, 2019.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Celeriac and apple mash with a twist]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/blog/Celeriac-apple-mash/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/blog/Celeriac-apple-mash</id>
  <published>2017-09-09T16:05:02+02:00</published>
  <updated>2017-09-09T16:05:02+02:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>António Domingues</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>amjdomingues@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;After being served celeriac and apple mash in Restaurants a few times I have been keen to replicate it at home. It is a quite tasty side, slightly on the sweet side, and very easy to prepare. Eventually I saw a recipe in a baby food book - and my bebé needed food - which served as a catalyst. I tried to achieve a recipe that is suitable for babies, about 1 year old, but also for adults.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/images/img/CeleriacAndAppleMash.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The bastard&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the above picture is how it got served for the baby, but for us we used it as a side for &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/blog/Pork-fillet-with-orange-and-mustard/&quot;&gt;pork fillet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;variations&quot;&gt;Variations&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess one could skip the popatoes. I have it in there to make it more substantial for the Bebé.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;inspiration&quot;&gt;Inspiration&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A dish served in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pollers.de/&quot;&gt;Pollers Häusje&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Servings: 4&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Prep Time:  15 mins&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cook Time:  30 mins&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Total Time: 45 mins&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Celeriac: 1, aprox. 500 grams, roughly cubbed in 0.5-1 cm pieces&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Granny smith apples: 2, aprox. 300 grams, quartered&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Potato: 1, roughly cubbed in 1 cm pieces&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Shallot, 1, roughly chopped&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bay leaves, 1&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Butter, 1 tablespoon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cream, 2 tablespoons&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sea salt: to taste&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Black Pepper: to taste&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Top the celeriac, peel it with a knife removing the rough bits. Peel the potato and core the apples, and cut everything into cubes (small if they are to prepare baby food).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Heat the butter in medium-high heat on a pot, and cook the onion for a couple of minutes. Add the celeriac, the potatoes and the apple and cook for another 5 minutes with the lid on.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add water up to 3/4 of the vegetables (the apple will cook with the vapor alone), heat until boiling an reduce the heat down to medium. Cover and cook for 15 to 20 minutes, or until tender.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Once the vegetables are soft, reserve half the liquid to a cup, add salt, pepper and cream, and puree. Add the reserved liquid to achieve the desired consistency.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Enjoy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/blog/Celeriac-apple-mash/&quot;&gt;Celeriac and apple mash with a twist&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by António Domingues at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on September 09, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chocolaty and Hazelnut tart]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/blog/Chocolate-hazelnut-tart/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/blog/Chocolate-hazelnut-tart</id>
  <published>2017-02-11T13:24:02+01:00</published>
  <updated>2017-02-11T13:24:02+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>António Domingues</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>amjdomingues@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;Do you love chocolate? And I don’t mean milk “chocolate”, I mean the real, raw stuff. Uncensored, unsweetened cocoa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the answer to the above question was “where is it and when can I have it?” then this recipe is for you. This is also one for those that don’t like evolved and complex dessert/cake recipes. It is doesn’t even require baking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/images/img/RawChocolateTart.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Intense&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Has can be seen from the picture, it goes very well as little something for your coffee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;variations&quot;&gt;Variations&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You can use small muffin forms instead of a large one.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Vanilla extract can also be vanilla sugar or flavoring.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;source&quot;&gt;Source&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I made little to no know changes to the original recipe taken from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ourpaleolife.com/recipe/chocolate-hazelnut-tart-paleo-vegan-raw/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Servings: 4&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Prep Time:  10 mins&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cooking Time:  20 mins&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Total Time:  30 mins&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Crust&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hazelnut flour: 90 grams&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Raw cocoa powder: 2 teaspoons&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Coconut oil, melted: 3 tablespoons&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Maple syrup: 1 tablespoons&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sea salt: a small pinch&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Filling&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Coconut oil: 3 tablespoons&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Full-fat coconut milk: 3 tablespoons&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Maple syrup: 3 tablespoons&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cocoa powder (I use half Natural, half Black Onyx): 6 tablespoons&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Vanilla extract: 1/2 teaspoon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mix all the ingredients for the crust in a bowl using a flat spoon or fork. Line a ~16 cm cake form with it. I did it in ceramic form, but a silicon form might make it easier to remove the cake.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For the filling heat melt the Coconut milk, Coconut oil, and maple syrup in a sauce pan.  Swirl occasionally and turn up the heat if it is taking too lomg for the coconut oil to mix (don’t let it boil). Once the mix is smooth, take from the heat and stir the cocoa powder and mix until smooth. Finally add the vanilla extract, and pour into the crust.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Store in the fridge for at least one hour before eating. Sprinkle each portion with shredded coconut for prettiness.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Enjoy!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/blog/Chocolate-hazelnut-tart/&quot;&gt;Chocolaty and Hazelnut tart&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by António Domingues at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on February 11, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pumpkin and Goat cheese pie with thyme]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/blog/Pumpkin-feta-pie/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/blog/Pumpkin-feta-pie</id>
  <published>2017-01-29T18:09:02+01:00</published>
  <updated>2017-01-29T18:09:02+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>António Domingues</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>amjdomingues@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;The Linguist also likes to cook and try new recipes. She also happens to read a newspaper, SZ to those in the know, that publishes some nice recipes in the weekend edition. Those tend to look nice, but also be on the elaborate side of “I can’t bother to buy all the ingredients”. This one however is just about easy enough to prepare and doesn’t require extravagant ingredients, so we decided to give a go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/images/img/PumpkinAndGoatCheesePie.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Burn!&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it turned out quite nicely. Ok, the pumpkin was a little dark, but I don’t mind and it was very tasty. Will do again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;variations&quot;&gt;Variations&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The original recipe had only 100 g of cream cheese. The package we bought had 150 g. We used it all and will not apologize for it.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Choose a relatively strong goat cream cheese, otherwise it will be hard for the flavor to come through.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;source&quot;&gt;Source&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A German &lt;a href=&quot;https://rezept.sz-magazin.de/rezept/kuerbis-tarte-mit-thymian-und-ziegenkaese/&quot;&gt;Newspaper&lt;/a&gt;. I translated from German to the best of my (and google’s translate) ability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Servings: 4&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Prep Time: 25 mins&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cooking Time: 65 mins&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Total Time: 90 mins&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Flour type 550: 200 g&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Butter: 100 g, cold&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cold water: 60 g, cold&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Vinegar: 1 tablespoon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Red Curi squash/Hokkaido: small one (~500 g), sliced&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Olive oil: 2 tablespoon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Honey: 2 tablespoon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Thyme: 4 sprigs&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Goat cream cheese: 150 g&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Eggs: 3&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Salt and pepper: to taste&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cayenne peper: a pinch&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pistachios unsalted: 20 g; roughly chopped.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mix the flour with 1/2 teaspoon of salt, and add flakes of butter. Finely crumble with the fingers until no coarse pieces of butter are left and the flour is still granular. Add the vinegar and the water, mix with a tablespoon, and knead with the hands until the dough is smooth (The Linguist cheated and used the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bosch-home.co.uk/products/food-preparation/accessories-for-kitchen-machines.html&quot;&gt;MUM&lt;/a&gt;). Shape it into a ball, and let it sit for 30-60 minutes in the fridge (you can wrap it in aluminum foil).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pre-heat the oven at 200ºc. Quarter the Hokkaido and de-seed. Cut it in thin slices.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In a bowl mix olive oil, honey, salt and pepper. Throw in pumkin slice to coat with this marinade.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lay the pumpkin slices in a baking tray covered with baking paper and roast for 20 minutes. Let it cool in the tray. Reduce the oven temperature to 180°c.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Coat a 23 cm pie form with butter and spread the dough. The Linguist puts the dough in the form and squashes it into shape with her hands and the bottom of a glass. Cover with baking paper and spread dried pods or dummy balls on top to prevent the dough from rising - we actually used lentils, but dried beans or chickpeas will also work. Pre-bake the dough for 15 minutes (middle shelf), remove the lentils (or whatever) and the baking paper and bake for another 10 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pick the Thyme leaves and chop them in very small pieces. Mix the eggs with cream cheese until it is an homogeneous cream. Add the thyme, salt, black and cayenne pepper. Pour the mixture in the pre-backed dough, spread the pumpkin on top and sprinkle the pistachio. Bake at 160°c for about 20 minutes, or until the filling is set and slightly brown.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Enjoy!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/blog/Pumpkin-feta-pie/&quot;&gt;Pumpkin and Goat cheese pie with thyme&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by António Domingues at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on January 29, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Feta and chouriço frittata]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/blog/Feta-chourico-frittata/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/blog/Feta-chourico-frittata</id>
  <published>2017-01-29T13:10:02+01:00</published>
  <updated>2017-01-29T13:10:02+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>António Domingues</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>amjdomingues@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;Frittatas. Omelets for the middle class. What I love about them as that the basic ingredients are usually in the house - eggs - and then one throw what it whatever is lying around the pantry/fridge. It can even be used to re-purpose left-overs. Adding veggies to it also makes it a very nourishing and nutritious meal. It is also easy to put together and is one of my go to recipes when I run out of ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/images/img/FetaFrittata.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;All the eggs!&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This recipe has Feta and chouriço, which are two of my favorite ingredients. Both very versatile and full of flavor and thus very little extra seasoning is needed. But don’t be bound to these ingredients. See variations for more ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I happen to be lucky enough to have flameproof roasting tin, which means that I can make the dish in one pot. However, I have previously prepared the frittata in a frying pan, or pot, and after mixing with the egg, transfered everything to a roasting tin and into the oven. No problem. Ah, yes, I have a kitchen aid thingy also know as &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bosch-home.co.uk/products/food-preparation/accessories-for-kitchen-machines.html&quot;&gt;MUM&lt;/a&gt; which turns the preparation of vegetables in to a child’s play. Before I used a Juliane peeler.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;variations&quot;&gt;Variations&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;With minced meat, fried with the onion, and chilies&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pumpkin, Feta and sage.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mushrooms. Very careful that it doesn’t get too soggy.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Butter will also do instead of the olive oil.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I like to add cream to the adds to bulk it up, but you can leave it out.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;source&quot;&gt;Source&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here and there. I took a basic &lt;a href=&quot;http://breakingmuscle.com/fuel/paleo-zucchini-frittata-recipe&quot;&gt;zucchini frittata recipe&lt;/a&gt; and have been making variations of it for while now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Servings: 6&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Prep Time: 15 mins&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cooking Time: 40 mins&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Total Time: 55 mins&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Eggs: 10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Carrots: 3, shredded&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Zuchini: 3, shredded&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Red bell pepper: 1, diced&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Parmigiano: 50 g, grated&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Feta: 200 g, cubed in small pieces&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Chouriço: 1, ~200 g, cubed in small pieces&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Onion: 1, chopped&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cream (or milk): 100 mL&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Parsley: large bunch, chopped&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Olive oil: 2 tablespoon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Salt and pepper: to taste&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In an oven-prof casserole (dutch oven) or a flameproof roasting tin (see picture above), heat the olive oil (medium heat) and fry the onion until translucent. Add the chouriço and the bell pepper, and fry until a bit of the fat starts leaking, then add the carrots, zucchini, season, and fry for another 10 minutes, or until soft.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;While the veggies are frying, start the oven at 175ºc, and whisk the eggs with the cream, some salt and pepper, and add in the Feta and the Parmigiano.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Take the casserole away from the heat, mix the egg with the veggies, and take it to the oven for 25 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Enjoy!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/blog/Feta-chourico-frittata/&quot;&gt;Feta and chouriço frittata&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by António Domingues at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on January 29, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pork fillet with orange and mustard]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/blog/Pork-fillet-with-orange-and-mustard/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/blog/Pork-fillet-with-orange-and-mustard</id>
  <published>2017-01-21T21:43:02+01:00</published>
  <updated>2017-01-21T21:43:02+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>António Domingues</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>amjdomingues@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;Not much to say about this dish except that it was very easy to prepare and tasted very nice indeed. The orange as a side (with some salad) is a &lt;a href=&quot;https://pt.wikipedia.org/wiki/Leit%C3%A3o_assado_%C3%A0_Bairrada&quot;&gt;classic&lt;/a&gt; from my neck of the woods, though it is usually served with fatty pork meat. This is the opposite, since it is very lean meat - it is a fillet after all - but still works great. The sauce was perfect, but the meat could have stayed longer in the marinade. I let it marinate for 2-3 hours and it could have been there for double that time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/images/img/PorkFilletWithOrange.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Warms me heart!.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all, another one of those dishes that require very little effort, and can prepared in advanced. It does need some time to marinate, so not something to do on a whim after coming home from work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;variations&quot;&gt;Variations&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Serve with a green leaves salad.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Marinate longer - at least 4-6 hours.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;source&quot;&gt;Source&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inspiration from a recipe published in a magazine of a large Portuguese supermarket chain, Continente. If you can read Portuguese, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://chef.continente.pt/&quot;&gt;sister website&lt;/a&gt; has plenty of good recipes with a very good search function.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Servings: 2&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Prep Time:  15 mins&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cooking Time:  60 mins&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Total Time:  75 mins&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pork fillet: 1, 500 grams&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Oranges: 4&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rosemary: 1 tablespoon, chopped&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Thyme: 1 tablespoon, leaves picked and chopped&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mustard: 2 tablespoon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Garlic: 3, crushed&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;White wine: 150 mL&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Olive oil: 1 tablespoon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Salt and pepper: to taste&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In a bowl make a paste with the mustard, olive oil, garlic, herbs, salt and pepper. Rub the pork fillet with it and lay it in the roasting pot.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Squeeze the juice of two of the oranges and pour over the fillet. Let it marinate in the fridge for a several hours.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Start the over at 200ºc and roast, with the lid on top, for about 45 minutes. Check after 30 min if the meat is nearly done.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;While it roasts, peel the other two oranges and cut them into slices (about 1/2 cm, see picture).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Once the meat is cooked, take it out and wrap it in aluminum foil to it warm and moist. Add white wine to roasting pan and scrape th bottom. If the roasting tin is not stove proof, transfer the sauce to a pot. Otherwise just heat it up and let the sauce boil for about 10 until its reduce to your taste.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Slice the meat and serve it with the oranges.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Enjoy!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/blog/Pork-fillet-with-orange-and-mustard/&quot;&gt;Pork fillet with orange and mustard&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by António Domingues at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on January 21, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cauliflower mash]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/blog/cauliflower-mash/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/blog/cauliflower-mash</id>
  <published>2017-01-19T21:53:02+01:00</published>
  <updated>2017-01-19T21:53:02+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>António Domingues</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>amjdomingues@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;Cauliflower mash is becoming one of my favorite side dishes. Very easy to prepare and versatile, it goes well with a number of dishes, specially &lt;a href=&quot;http://weekendfamily.github.io/foodforthepeople/blog/easy-chicken-stew/&quot;&gt;stews&lt;/a&gt;. This version is more evolved, with the spring onion and bacon making it almost a main course on it’s own, but remove that and you are left with an incredible, and healthy, complement to most meals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/images/img/CauliflowerMash.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Power&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;variations&quot;&gt;Variations&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The spring onion and bacon are extras and not needed for the basic mash.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you don’t have creme fraiche at hand any heavy cream will do. I have used greek yogurt in a pinch.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You can also add a dollop of butter.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;source&quot;&gt;Source&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ibreatheimhungry.com/2012/01/better-than-potatoes-cheesy-cauliflower.html&quot;&gt;This&lt;/a&gt; is a good, creamy cauliflower recipe, and the idea for the bacon from someplace whose link I cannot find.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Servings: 4&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Prep Time:  10 mins&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cooking Time:  20 mins&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Total Time:  30 mins&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cauliflower: 2 heads, cut into florets&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Creme fraiche: 150g&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Parmigiano: 50 g, grated&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Garlic: 1 clove, minced&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Spring onion: 1 bunch, thinly sliced&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bacon cubes: 150 g&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Salt and pepper: to taste&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Nutmeg: to taste&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Boil the cauliflower florets for about 15 minutes or until soft in water with a little salt.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;While the cauliflower cooks, gently fry the bacon in a frying pan at medium heat for about 5 minutes. It should not need any fat other than it’s own. Add the spring onion and fry until cooked (about 5 minutes). Reserve.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Once the cauliflower is cooked, strain it removing as much water as possible. This is critical as otherwise the mash will be a little runny.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add the creme fraiche and cheese, season with salt, pepper and the nutmeg, and blend it all together.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Serve with a topping of the bacon and spring onion.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Enjoy!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/blog/cauliflower-mash/&quot;&gt;Cauliflower mash&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by António Domingues at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on January 19, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Easy chicken stew]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/blog/easy-chicken-stew/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/blog/easy-chicken-stew</id>
  <published>2017-01-19T21:20:02+01:00</published>
  <updated>2017-01-19T21:20:02+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>António Domingues</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>amjdomingues@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;So, I am living abroad, still honing my cooking skills and I start thinking of all the tasty food my mum used to do, but I can’t quite replicate. I am really aching for some comfort food in the form of a stew. What to do?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, go straight to the source: call home. So I did. Multiple times in fact because I kept forgetting the recipe. Hopefully writing it here will prevent that in that future. Not that I mind calling home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, this recipe ticks all the boxes for me:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;it can be prepared in a few minutes;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;requires almost no supervision while cooking, which means can one do something else whilst it cooks, for instance take a shower;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;minimal cooking skills;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;minimal set of ingredients;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;dead cheap;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Works for dinner parties;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;can be prepared in advance for guests;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;tasty.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is also one of those that can be prepared in the morning, let it marinate all day, and then quickly cook in the evening. In fact, marinating will improve the taste.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/images/img/ChickenStew.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Warms me heart!.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see in the picture it was served with some nice &lt;a href=&quot;http://weekendfamily.github.io/foodforthepeople/blog/cauliflower-mash/&quot;&gt;cauliflower mash&lt;/a&gt;, but potato mash or rice will do. I sometimes add extra carrots as side. Or just serve some bread on the side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;When in doubt, add parsley.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;variations&quot;&gt;Variations&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Can of tomatoes won’t hurt.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Piri-piri.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Beer (lager or Pils) or dry white work equally well.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Marinating for a few hours really adds flavor.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you don’t have paprika paste, replace with sliced red paprika.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Don’t go too cheap on the chicken meat. If you can find it, a free range chicken will do wonders. No need to be corn fed though. My mum’s chicken eat whatever they can pick from the floor, including oranges all year around, and the meat tastes great.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;source&quot;&gt;Source&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Me mum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Servings: 4&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Prep Time:  15 mins&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cooking Time:  60 mins&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Total Time:  75 mins&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Chicken thighs: 4&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Carrots: 8, roughly chopped&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Beer (lager): 200 mL&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Onion: 2, chopped&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Parsley: large bunch, chopped&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bay leaves: 2&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tomato paste: 1 tablespoon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Paprika paste: 1 tablespoon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Olive oil: 1 tablespoon (optional)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Salt and pepper: to taste&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Piri-piri: to taste&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Separate chicken thighs from legs, clean, and put in a pan. Add all other ingredients and gently turn the meat once or twice. Cover with a lid and let it sit for a few hours in the fridge to acquire taste or proceed to step 2 if hungry.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Heat until it starts boiling, about 10 minutes, and then reduce to a gentle simmer. Cook for another 40-60 minutes until the meat is nearly falling off the bone. If you want to reduce the sauce, take the lid off for the last 15 minutes or so. Check for taste at this point and adjust seasoning.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Enjoy!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/blog/easy-chicken-stew/&quot;&gt;Easy chicken stew&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by António Domingues at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on January 19, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Celeriac gratin]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/blog/celeriac-gratin/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/blog/celeriac-gratin</id>
  <published>2016-12-23T17:00:02+01:00</published>
  <updated>2016-12-23T17:00:02+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>António Domingues</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>amjdomingues@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;This blog has been lacking something. New recipes for one. But also something fancy and something that I have not yet done, but will do this Christmas. So if you prepared it before the 25th you are on your own. Also no picture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And this recipe? Well, I am big fan of celeriac as a side dish and anything will cheese, namely &lt;em&gt;gratins&lt;/em&gt; will make me heart warm. So when I saw the filling for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2016/dec/12/vegetarian-christmas-lunch-anna-jones-modern-cook&quot;&gt;this recipe&lt;/a&gt; in The Guardian [of Manchester] I immediately saw an opportunity to impress my in-laws. More on that later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;variations&quot;&gt;Variations&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the original recipe a few things were changed:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;no crust obviously&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;way less honey, 1 tablespoon became 1 teaspoon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;half of the herbs were used, though I probably should have used all of it.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I forgot to grate 1/3 of the celeriac&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Celeriac was cubbed and fried in 2 tablespoon of olive olive oil for about 10 minutes, instead of boiling. I hoped this would give it a bit more flavor.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cheddar was replaced with 100 g Emmentaler and 150 g of Gruyére.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;source&quot;&gt;Source&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2016/dec/12/vegetarian-christmas-lunch-anna-jones-modern-cook&quot;&gt;source&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Servings: 6&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Prep Time:  30 mins&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cooking Time:  45 mins&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Total Time:  75 mins&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Celeriac: 1kg, or about 1-2 heads, cubbed.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Garlic,: 3 heads, cloves separated and peeled&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cheddar cheese: 220g, coarsely grated&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Creme fraiche: 150g&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Olive oil: 1 tablespoon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Balsamic vinegar: 1 tablespoon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Honey: 1 tablespoon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rosemary: 2 sprigs, leaves picked and finely chopped&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Thyme: 2 sprigs, leaves picked and finely chopped&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sage: 2 sprigs, leaves picked and finely chopped&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lemon juice: half a lemon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mustard: 1 tablespoon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Parsley: small bunch, chopped&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Eggs: 2, beaten&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Salt and pepper: to taste&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Simmer the garlic cloves for 2-3 minutes, then drain.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Using the same pan (dried), fry the garlic in olive oil on a high heat for 2 minutes. Add the balsamic vinegar and 200 ml of water, bring to the boil and simmer for 10 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Add the honey, most of the rosemary and thyme (save a little, with the sage) and salt. Cook on medium heat for another 5 minutes, or until most of the liquid has evaporated. The the garlic cloves should be coated in a dark syrup.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;While the sauce is thickening, peel the celeriac and cut it into quarters, setting aside about 1/3. Slice the rest in 2 cm-thick pieces. Boil these pieces in hot water for 7-10 minutes. Drain. Meantime, grate the remaining celeriac.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;In bowl mix the boiled celeriac, cheese, creme fraiche, lemon juice, mustard, parsley and eggs. Add salt and grind of pepper and gently fold in the caramelized garlic cloves.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Preheat the oven to 160C/325F/gas mark 3. Coat lightly an over form with olive oil, and then add the mix, grated celeriac, rosemary, thyme, all the sage, and finish with a drizzle of olive oil. Bake for 45 minutes or until it has set and the top is golden brown.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/blog/celeriac-gratin/&quot;&gt;Celeriac gratin&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by António Domingues at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on December 23, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Seafood and bean stew]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/blog/Seafoof-and-beans/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/blog/Seafoof-and-beans</id>
  <published>2016-11-07T21:11:02+01:00</published>
  <updated>2016-11-07T21:11:02+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>António Domingues</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>amjdomingues@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;I am not the biggest fish fan, but sometimes I just feel like having seafood. This is variation of the classic Portuguese &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Feijoada&quot;&gt;Feijoada&lt;/a&gt;, which has very little to do with the original. Then again Feijoada means “made from beans”, this dish has beans. The white beans and seafood are very nice combination, and the parsley is staple of Portuguese cuisine. When in doubt, add parsley.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/images/img/SeafoodAndBeans.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cabbage!.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As per usual this recipe can be made with readily available ingredients and is very easy as fast to prepare. It is also quite tasty and nutritious. I sometimes add some Piri-piri or chili to give it a bit more humph, but if the chouriço is spicy it will give enough flavor to the dish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;variations&quot;&gt;Variations&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Both the carrots and the peas are not in the original recipe and I use them to bulk up the dish, but one could omit them. I could remove the peas, they don’t add much to the flavor, but I really the carrots in this dish.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you feel fancy try some fish stock. The original recipe did not have any stock at all, so it could be omitted. I like to add it for extra flavor.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Thawing theSeafood in advance is a good idea, but if you don’t, just cook it for another 10 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;source&quot;&gt;Source&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of my favorite &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.saborintenso.com/f40/feijoada-frutos-do-mar-10464/&quot;&gt;sources&lt;/a&gt; for Portuguese recipes. There is also a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/user/saborintensocom&quot;&gt;youtube channel&lt;/a&gt; which sometimes help for more elaborate dishes. Portuguese only though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Servings: 6&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Prep Time:  10 mins&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cooking Time:  25 mins&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Total Time:  35 mins&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Frozen seafood: 1 kg&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Canned white beans: 1 kg&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Canned tomatoes: 400 grams&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Carrots: 4, chopped&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Frozen peas: 200 grams&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Chouriço: ~100 grams, half of one&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Onion: 1, large&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Garlic: 3&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Vegetable stock: ~150 mL&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Parsley: small bunch (save some to garnish)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Olive oil: 8 tablespoon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Salt and pepper: to taste&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Heat the olive oil in a pot, and fry gently the onions and garlic.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add the tomatoes, seafood and chouriço. Season with salt and pepper, mix everything and cook in low heat for 10 minutes (if the seafood is frozen, cook for 15 min).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add the beans (after removing the liquid they come in), carrots, and peas. Add stock until it is covered. If needed add some water. Add the bunch of parsley and mix. Cook for another 10 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Serve with some chopped parsley.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Enjoy!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/blog/Seafoof-and-beans/&quot;&gt;Seafood and bean stew&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by António Domingues at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on November 07, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Salmon and Cabbage with Dill Vinaigrette]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/blog/Salmon-and-cabbage/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/blog/Salmon-and-cabbage</id>
  <published>2016-11-07T21:11:02+01:00</published>
  <updated>2016-11-07T21:11:02+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>António Domingues</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>amjdomingues@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;I must confess: I love cabbage. It goes well with any number of dishes, nutritious, has a wonderful green color, and comes in many variates. I am still skeptikal about green smoothies, and have profound dislike for the current Kale love. My forefathers grew &lt;a href=&quot;https://pt.wikipedia.org/wiki/Repolho&quot;&gt;Repolho&lt;/a&gt; before any hipster donned its first cap!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cabbage is a serious matter for me. Anyway, I got hold of this recipe and though it was a interesting combination of salmon and Vegetable king, and the Dill vinagrette intrigued me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/images/img/SalmonAndCabbage.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cabbage!.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Who am I kidding? I wanted a cabbage dish and there was not a lot of time to prepare it. This fitted the bill. It also turned out to have a wonderful flavor with the dill and lemon combining well with the cabbage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;variations&quot;&gt;Variations&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I have a Kumquat tree which happens to have fruits at the moment. I took a Kumquat and squeezed the juice on top of the salmon before sticking it in the oven for extra citrus flavor.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The recipe states Dijon mustard, and I kept because it sounds fancy. In fact, I used the rest of an old Bautzen mustard jar.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The original recipe had 2 types of cabbage, Kale and Savoy. The hipsters took all the Grühnkohl from the supermaket. No problem. It worked nicely with just the Savoy and it sounds frencher.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;source&quot;&gt;Source&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This Martha Stewart &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Low-Diet-Cookbook-Smart-Carb-Recipes/dp/156924359X&quot;&gt;book&lt;/a&gt; on our shelve for while and even though we made a few recipes, it seems underused. This recipe came from there and it was a hit, so hopefully there will be more to come.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Servings: 4&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Prep Time:  15 mins&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Total Time:  35 mins&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Salmon: 4 fillets&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Savoy cabbage: 1 large head&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dill: small bunch&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lemon: 1, juice and zest&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Olive oil: 8 tablespoon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dijon mustard: 1 teaspoon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Salt and pepper: to taste&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Heat the oven to 230ºc. Take the cabbage leaves, remove the hard steams and cut in thin slices. Put it in a roasting tray, drizzle with 2 tablespoons of olive oil, salt and pepper to taste, mixing it all. Put in the oven for 6 minutes. Once done, mix it all again, lay the salmon on top and season with salt and pepper. Roast everything for about 10 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In a bowl mix the left-over olive oil (6 tablespoons), the chopped dill, mustard, and lemon juice and zest.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Serve drizzling the vinaigrette on top of the salmon and cabbage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;


    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/blog/Salmon-and-cabbage/&quot;&gt;Salmon and Cabbage with Dill Vinaigrette&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by António Domingues at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on November 07, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Peas with pouched egg and chouriço]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/blog/Peas-with-poached-eggs/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/blog/Peas-with-poached-eggs</id>
  <published>2016-10-22T14:55:02+02:00</published>
  <updated>2016-10-22T14:55:02+02:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>António Domingues</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>amjdomingues@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;This is one my go to dishes when the winter comes. Filling, healthy and made with ingredients that are usually laying around, it makes for great comfort food. Even though this dish is fairly common in Portugal, I had for the first time in England with some friends. I think it might be more of a Southern dish. Anyway, it was love at first site and since them I have done it quite often.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;variations&quot;&gt;Variations&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In the absence of bacon I have used lard instead of olive oil for that nice pork flavor.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Some &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Piri_piri#Piri_piri_sauce&quot;&gt;Piri-Piri&lt;/a&gt; is a wellcome addition for those that like it hot.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If chouriço is not available, then consider adding sweet paprika. Not quite the same though.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Instead of white wine, beer will do. Something dry like lager or Pilsner.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;inspiration&quot;&gt;Inspiration&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I followed the recipe from this &lt;a href=&quot;http://lifestyle.sapo.pt/sabores/receitas/ervilhas-estufadas-com-ovos-escalfados&quot;&gt;Portuguese website&lt;/a&gt;, which is one of may regular sources of inspiration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Servings: 4&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Prep Time:  10 mins&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cook Time:  45 minutes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Total Time: 55 mins&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cauliflower mash&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Frozen peas: 1 kg&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Canned tomatoes: 1 can, 400 mL&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Chouriço: 1, aprox., sliced&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bacon cubes: 100 grams&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Eggs: 4&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Garlic cloves: 2, chopped&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Onion: 1, chopped&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Chicken stock: 200 mL&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;White wine: 150 mL&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Water: 100 mL&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Olive oil: 2 tablespoons&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sea salt: to taste&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Take the peas out of the freezer.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;In medium heat, gently fry the onion and garlic with the olive oil in a pot. When its fragrant, add the chouriço and the bacon and fry it until it gains come color.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Add the tomatoes, mix it all together, and cook for 5 minutes. Then add the wine and as soon as it starts boiling, the stock. Let it cook for another 5 minutes. At this point, season with salt if needed.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Stir in the peas (even if they are still a little frozen), and add water until they are covered. Lower, the heat, put a lid on, and let it cook for 15 minutes or until it is cooked.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Taste the sauce and the peas to adjust the seasoning and check if peaks are cooked. If so, carefully break the eggs one by one and let them slide to the stew. You can make little pockets in the peas before this, so that the eggs are fairly separated from each other. Let it cook for another 5 minutes and it’s done.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/blog/Peas-with-poached-eggs/&quot;&gt;Peas with pouched egg and chouriço&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by António Domingues at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on October 22, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Stew with Uzbek spices]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/blog/Lamb-stew-with-caulifower-mash/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/blog/Lamb-stew-with-caulifower-mash</id>
  <published>2016-10-08T18:15:02+02:00</published>
  <updated>2016-10-08T18:15:02+02:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>António Domingues</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>amjdomingues@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;I had some friends over and decided to make some nice and different. Also something that could be prepared in advance and be hot and ready for them. A stew (or slow cooked dish) is always a good choice especially now that the cold weather is upon us. To make it a little different, I went with lamb… who am I kidding? Lamb is one of my favorite meats and I use any excuse to eat it. The Uzbek spice mix is also something quite different but not too different that would raise high brows from more nit-picky guests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a side, the cauliflower mash brings it’s own flavor to the table, without overpowering the main course. This mash is fast becoming one of my favorite side dishes for its ease of preparation, and taste… and it takes no time to prepare!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In end the guests were quite happy - the wine might have had something to do with it - and ate everything. I call it a success, my mom would say I should have made more food and the guest left the house hungry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is no picture of the food, but I have one of the classic Portuguese roasting pot used to prepare it. Made of clay it is excellent to make one pot dishes in the oven.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/images/img/ClayPot.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Some fancy stuff&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;variations&quot;&gt;Variations&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Beef can be used instead of the lamb. I did it with a cheap cut, and must that due to nature of meat - lamb doesn’t need to cooked for a long time and beef sometimes gets better with longer cooking times - beef can be even better.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I sometimes add carrots cut in chunks to the stew to have extra portion of veggies. Add the carrots to pot about 1 hour before it finishes cooking to have them crunchy, or from the beginning if you prefer them soft.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;[vegetarian] I have not tried it, but this spice mix could be a good basis for a vegetarian curry/stew.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use a Crockpot (slow cooker), or simmer it in a stove.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use double the amount of red wine (old open bottle) instead of the red wine vinegar. Trick learned from poorer times.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Increase the amount of cayenne pepper for extra punch.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;inspiration&quot;&gt;Inspiration&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Originally I saw the sauce in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.de/Webers-Grillbibel-GU-Weber-Grillen/dp/3833818638/&quot;&gt;Weber’s Grill Bibel&lt;/a&gt; and it was to marinate lamb chops. During a botched BBQ party - it rained - I had the sauce prepared and the only way to use it was a stew with beef. It worked. From the original I doubled the amounts of Thyme and Cumin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Servings: 7&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Prep Time:  30 mins&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cook Time:  4 hours&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Total Time: 4 hours 30 mins&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cauliflower mash&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Caulifower: 2 large heads&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Parmesan: 4 tablespoons&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cream cheese: 4 tablespoons&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Butter: 2 tablespoons&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Black pepper: to taste&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sea salt: to taste&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Lamb stew&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Leg of lamb: about 1.8 Kg&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Canned tomatoes: 1 can, 400 mL&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Onion: 2, roughly chopped&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Garlic: 4, roughly chopped&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Olive oil: 120 mL&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Red wine vinegar: 10 mL&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sweet paprika: 2 tablespoons&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Thyme: 2 Tablespoons, fresh or dry&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Coriander seeds: 1 tablespoon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cumin: 1 tablespoon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cayenne pepper: 1 teaspoon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Black pepper: to taste, if available use pepper with citrus flavor&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sea salt: to taste&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cauliflower mash&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Trim and discard the green leaves of the caulifower and separate the florets. Boil for about 10 minutes (or until soft) with a pinch of salt.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Drain the cauliflower very well, and in bowl (or pot) add the other ingredients. Puré with a blender until smooth. Add some more salt if needed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Lamb stew&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Pre-heat the oven at 180ºc.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;To prepare the sauce, blend all the ingredient - except the lamb - with a blender.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;De-bone the meat, and cut it in 1-2 cm thick chunks, put in a stove-proof pot (with a lid!), mix the sauce, cover the pot, and stick it in the oven.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Cook for about 30 minutes, and then lower the temperature to 150ºc. Cook for another 3-3 and half hours. Serve in a rustic pot with the side of Cauliflower mash.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For the sauce, pour off excess fat from the frying pan and place over a high heat. Pour in the port, stirring to deglaze, and let bubble for a minute. Add the cranberry jam and reduce the heat. Mix the cornflour with a splash of cold water to dissolve, and add it to the pan mixing well. Let it bubble until the liquid has the desired consistency. If it gets too thick, add a splash of water and mix.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Add any juices from the resting duck. Taste and adjust the seasoning and add some jam or orange juice if desired.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Slice the duck breasts on the diagonal and fan them out on warmed serving plates. Spoon the sauce around the duck and serve with the mashed celery root.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;


    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/blog/Lamb-stew-with-caulifower-mash/&quot;&gt;Stew with Uzbek spices&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by António Domingues at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on October 08, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hommous]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/blog/Hommous/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/blog/Hommous</id>
  <published>2016-10-03T18:11:02+02:00</published>
  <updated>2016-10-03T18:11:02+02:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>António Domingues</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>amjdomingues@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;This a staple or middle-eastern food but it is far from exotic to prepare. Very flexible it can be eaten as a snack/starter at an house party - also easy to carry - or as a main dish in a light meal. The Hommous can be scooped with some bread, though I prefer the lighter/healthier variant of using some carrot and/or cucumber sticks. I have not tried it myself, but make it smooth, and it can be part of a leafy salad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hommous is also one of those dishes that are available pre-prepared in supermarkets, but it takes so little time and effort, that I don’t see why one should not take control of the ingredients that one ingests instetad of byuing something with added (unnecessary) ingredients: all you need are some canned chickpeas, tahini, lemon, garlic and you are set to go. All things that I keep in the pantry for an emergency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/images/img/Hommous.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The middle east at the tip of your carrot.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though the paprika and parsley are optional, I like the color and flavor that they bring. And this is the basic version. There some more elaborate versions of the dish, but judging from who successful this version has been with friends, I will keep it simple - the People does not over-complicate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;source&quot;&gt;Source&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A very good &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Low-Diet-Cookbook-Smart-Carb-Recipes/dp/156924359X&quot;&gt;book&lt;/a&gt; with Low GI recipes: The Low GI Diet Cookbook: 100 Simple, Delicious Smart-Carb Recipes. Though now I tend to go with lower carb recipes, this book still has some pretty good recipes that I find worth revisiting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Servings: to share, or 2 as main&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Prep Time:  20 mins&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Total Time:  20 mins&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Chickpeas: 400 grams, canned (keep the liquid)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tahini: 135 grams&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Garlic: 2 cloves (crushed)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lemon: 1, juice&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Salt and pepper: to taste&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Olive oil: 1 tablespoon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Paprika: a pinch (optional)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Parsley: 1 tablespoon (optional)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Combine the chickpeas, tahini, garlic, lemon juice, salt and pepper in a food processor. Add some of chickpeas liquid until it acquires the desired consistency - it should be a smooth paste, I prefer it on the thick side but some people prefer it smoother.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Serve in a bowl. Drizzle with olive oil, and decorate with the parsley and paprika.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Serve with carrot/cucumber cut into small sticks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;


    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/blog/Hommous/&quot;&gt;Hommous&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by António Domingues at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on October 03, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Parsnip, garlic and blue cheese]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/blog/Parsnip-and-blue-cheese/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/blog/Parsnip-and-blue-cheese</id>
  <published>2016-09-20T21:00:02+02:00</published>
  <updated>2016-09-20T21:00:02+02:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>António Domingues</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>amjdomingues@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;When I first saw this recipe I was a little suspicious: blue cheese? Parsnip? But we took a gamble because there were a lot of parsnips in the market and sometimes it is nice to get out of one’s comfort zone, and this time it was well worth it. This recipe makes for a very creamy and soup, without being too intense. Served very hot its wonderful for the cold Autumn evenings that are starting to appear. So don’t be afraid of stepping out of your comfort zone and try this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;variations&quot;&gt;Variations&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The original recipe call for two garlic bulbs, but I thought that is a bit much and do it with only one. If you are a garlic lover, go for it.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I usually do 100g of cheese because the packages are… 100g.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;inspiration&quot;&gt;Inspiration&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a recipe from my favorite cookbook: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Hughs-Three-Good-Things-Fearnley-Whittingstall/dp/1408828588&quot;&gt;Three Good Things (… on a plate)&lt;/a&gt; by Hugh Fearnley-Whittingstall. The book is excellent in that most recipes require easy to source ingredients, the cooking techniques are pretty easy, and so far all those that I have tried were very tasty. Not all recipes are For The People, but the ratio of useful recipes and “look at me I know fancy ingredients” is in favor of the thrifty chap in me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you don’t fancy getting the book, some of the recipes are available in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/series/hugh-s-three-good-things-on-a-plate&quot;&gt;The Guardian&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Servings: 4 as starter or 2 as main course.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Prep Time:  10 mins&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cook Time:  50 mins&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Total Time: 60 mins&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Parsnip: 500 grams, roughly cubbed 1-2 cm pieces&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Blue cheese: 50 grams&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Vegetable stock: 600mL, hot&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Onion: 1, sliced&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Garlic bulb: 1&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Olive oil: 3 tablespoons&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sea salt: to taste&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Black Pepper: to taste&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Preheat oven to 190ºc. Cut the top and bottom of the parsnips, peel and cut in chunks. Put them in an baking tray with the onions, add 2 tablespoons of olive oil, salt and pepper. Toss to mix.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cut the top of the garlic bulb to expose the garlic cloves. Put on top of a piece of aluminum foil, drizzle with the a tablespoon of olive oil, add salt and pepper and make a rough wrap with the aluminum foil and nest it in the middle of the parsnips. Pop in the oven for 40-50 min, until the parsnips are golden and cooked. You can poke the garlic with a tip of a knife to check if they are soft inside the skin. If not, cook for a little longer.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Time for a blender. Transfer the parsnips and onions to it, and squeeze the soft garlic from their skin. Transfer also the olive oil still in the wrap (it will be very fragrant), and add the vegetable stock and blue cheese. Blend it until smooth. If needed, add some hot water until it acquires the desired consistency. Serve and add salt and pepper to taste.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Enjoy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/blog/Parsnip-and-blue-cheese/&quot;&gt;Parsnip, garlic and blue cheese&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by António Domingues at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on September 20, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Salmon and spinach in a bed of celeriac]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/blog/Salmon-Spinach-and-egg/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/blog/Salmon-Spinach-and-egg</id>
  <published>2016-09-20T21:00:02+02:00</published>
  <updated>2016-09-20T21:00:02+02:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>António Domingues</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>amjdomingues@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;This recipe started as a recommendation from my sister, after she saw it in a cooking show o Portuguese TV. In it there are quintessential Portuguese ingredients like salted Cod, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alheira&quot;&gt;Alheira&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Broa&quot;&gt;Broa&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rapini&quot;&gt;Grelos&lt;/a&gt;. I made this recipe once with the proper ingredients, but I don’t always have the time to go the Portuguese grocery store. So through an iterative process of bastardization, Grelos became spinach, Cod is now salmon, and Alheira/Broa are nowhere to be seen, and out of nowhere came the celeriac. This new recipe is now something that most people can do with ingredients that are readily available, looks goods and tastes wonderfully fresh and different.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do not fear &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bbcgoodfood.com/glossary/celeriac&quot;&gt;celeriac&lt;/a&gt;! It is wonderful vegetable, very versatile whose flavor has a hint of sweetness and is a (very) watered down version of the more pungent stalks. The eggs combines wonderfully with the salmon and adds some color to the dish - as we say “os olhos também comem” (~ eyes also eat).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/images/img/SpinachAndSalmon.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The bastard&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The results is dish full of flavor with citrus notes without being overpowering. As it is custom in Food For the People, it was prepared with some frozen ingredients (Salmon and Spinach) which makes it relatively easy to prepare when there is no time to do some fresh grocery shopping after work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;variations&quot;&gt;Variations&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.joseavillez.pt/jdownloads/Receitas/Receitas_S1/receita_p2_15jun_lascas_bacalhau.pdf&quot;&gt;original recipe&lt;/a&gt; which I will translate one of these days.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Thyme instead of rosemary.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For the fish, I should try haddock one of these days.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Take the fish away and you will have a vegetarian dish.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chard&quot;&gt;Swiss Chard&lt;/a&gt; could also replace the spinach and it combines very well with orange.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;inspiration&quot;&gt;Inspiration&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The inspiring recipe can be found &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.joseavillez.pt/jdownloads/Receitas/Receitas_S1/receita_p2_15jun_lascas_bacalhau.pdf&quot;&gt;here (Portuguese)&lt;/a&gt; and it is a creation of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.joseavillez.pt&quot;&gt;Chef José Avillez&lt;/a&gt;. That said, the recipe has changed so much that is bares little resemblance with the original. Full bastardization has been completed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the fried celeriac I stole the recipe from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jamieoliver.com/recipes/vegetables-recipes/simple-as-that-celeriac/&quot;&gt;Jamie Oliver&lt;/a&gt; and improvised with the herbs I had at home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Servings: 2&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Prep Time:  15 mins&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cook Time:  35 mins&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Total Time: 50 mins&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Celeriac: 1, roughly cubbed in 0.5-1 cm pieces&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Salmon fillet: 2, aprox. 250 grams&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Spinach, 500 grams&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Eggs: 2&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lemon: 1, zest&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Orange: 1, juice&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rosemary leaves, 1 tablespoon, chopped&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Olive oil: 3 tablespoons, extra to brush&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Garlic clove: 1, sliced&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sea salt: to taste&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Black Pepper: to taste&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Top the celeriac, peel it with a knife removing the rough bits, and cut into 1 cm cubes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Put a casserole-type pan on a medium-high heat and add 2 tablespoons of olive oil. Once warm, add the celeriac cubes, thyme leaves and lemon zest. Add some salt, mix it all together, and turn the heat down to medium. Cover and cook for 20 to 25 minutes, or until tender. Mix it every know and then.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Preheat oven to 220ºc. Brush the Salmon fillets with olive oil, and season with salt and pepper. Pop in in the oven for about 15 minutes or until it starts tearing apart when you put a fork to it. Once done, flake it and put it aside.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Once the celeric is done (it’s soft and slightly brown), remove it from the pan, add some olive oil if needed and sauté the spinach with the garlic in the same pan. As it wilts, add the salmon, orange juice and mix it all together at low eat.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fry the eggs sunny side up in a thin layer of olive oil.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;On a deep plate or bowl, layer the celeriac, the salmon spinach mix, and top it off with the egg.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Enjoy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/blog/Salmon-Spinach-and-egg/&quot;&gt;Salmon and spinach in a bed of celeriac&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by António Domingues at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on September 20, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Liver and Chicken hearts stew with cabbage and parsnip chips]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/blog/Liver-and-Chicken-hearts-stew/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/blog/Liver-and-Chicken-hearts-stew</id>
  <published>2016-09-16T18:12:02+02:00</published>
  <updated>2016-09-16T18:12:02+02:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>António Domingues</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>amjdomingues@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;When the sun starts setting early, the body starts aching for some more substantial food, and salads no long have an appeal. it is time for an earthy dish, with one of the most nutritious, flavorsome, and yet vilified, organ meats: liver. It is also a very cheap meat that and cooks extremely fast. To add to the Autumnal feel of this dish, there is also cabbage and parsnip. All in all a very healthy and flavorsome dish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;variations&quot;&gt;Variations&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of the hearts and liver, you can use just one of those, or replace them with giblets. Additionally, spicy it up with more piri-piri and serve it as a snack with a beer (or two) and friends. This variation is very popular in Portugal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The parsnip fries will go well with other dishes, specially roasts. You can also experiment with other spices or herbs, for instance Rosemary, instead of the paprika.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And how to pick the best &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chorizo&quot;&gt;Chouriço&lt;/a&gt; you ask? Actually, for this dish the &lt;em&gt;best&lt;/em&gt; chouriço is not what you are looking for. The best one is mostly meat, and very little fat, which excellent as a &lt;em&gt;petisco&lt;/em&gt; (appetizer or &lt;em&gt;Tapas&lt;/em&gt;). For this dish however, you want one with fast which will release the nice spices into the sauce. We call it “Chouriço corrente”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;inspiration&quot;&gt;Inspiration&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the stew the starting point was a classical &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.saborintenso.com/f21/petisco-moelas-323/&quot;&gt;Portuguese giblets snack&lt;/a&gt; which I replaced with liver and hearths because my SO is not fond of giblets. The cabbage was a serendipitous experiment one day that there was some left over in the fridge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are plenty of parsnip fries in the interwebs, but &lt;a href=&quot;http://ahouseinthehills.com/2014/02/04/paprika-parsnip-fries/&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; is one of the simplest ones. My version is pretty much the same - without the extra sauce - and adjusted for my oven.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Servings: 4&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Prep Time:  30 mins&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cook Time:  40 mins&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Total Time: 70 mins&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Stew&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;chiken hearts and livers: 1000 g, frozen&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Savoy cabbage: half, diced&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Onion: 1, chopped&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Garlic: 2, chopped&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Butter: 2 tablespoon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;White wine: 3 dl, or lager/IPA/bitter beer&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Water: 2 dl&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Chouriço: 70 grams, cubbed in small chunks&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tomato paste: 6 tablespoons&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bay leaves: 3&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Piri-piri: to taste, can be replaced with dried chilies&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Salt: to taste, can be replaced with dried chilies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Parsnip chips&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Parsnips: 6, about 500 grams&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Olive oil: 1 tablespoon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Paprika: to taste, about a teaspoon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sea salt: to taste&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Parsnip fries&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Preheat oven to 190ºc.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Peel the parsnips - a potato peeler will do - chop the tops off, and cut in fries.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mix the parsnips with the olive oil, paprika and salt, and lay in a roasting tin covered with baking paper. Roast for 25 minutes, turn them and roast for another 10 minutes. Mind you times may vary depending on your oven.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Red Curi Squash mash&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Thaw the the liver and hearts, wash with cold water, remove extra fat, dry with kitchen paper and cut the livers in half.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In a pot, fry the livers in butter for about 5 minutes in medium heat until they are half-done. They will finish cooking later in the stew. Removed them from the pot and set aside.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If needed add some more butter to the pan, and gently fry onion and garlic. Also add the bay leaves.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;After about 5 minutes, or when the onion is translucent, add the chouriço frying it for a little bit to release some of the spices and fat, and then hearts mixing it all together. Add some salt and the chilies/piri-piri, cover the pot and fry for 5 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Throw in the tomato paste, wine and water, mix it all up, cook for another 10 minutes and then add the cabbage. In the closed pot the cabbage will wilt during the cooking. Let it cook for about 15 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add the livers, mix it all up so it can gain extra flavor from the sauce and cook for another 5 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/blog/Liver-and-Chicken-hearts-stew/&quot;&gt;Liver and Chicken hearts stew with cabbage and parsnip chips&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by António Domingues at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on September 16, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tahini and tuna salad]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/blog/Tahini-and-tuna-salad/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/blog/Tahini-and-tuna-salad</id>
  <published>2016-09-15T20:00:02+02:00</published>
  <updated>2016-09-15T20:00:02+02:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>António Domingues</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>amjdomingues@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;Summer is now almost over, but it is still warm enough for salads. And a salad does not need to be a sad affair, even if the ingredients are run of the mill, as I have been discovering. This one has Tuna in it to remind me of the Ocean, which I dearly miss, and tahini (sesame paste) to make me feel fancy. The halloumi is there to bulk it up and make it a proper main dish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/images/img/TunaTahiniSalad.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Tuna salad for the win&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fancy ingredients, tahini and halloumi, can be found in large supermarkets, health food stores or Turkish/Middle Eastern stores, and they keep for long, specially the tahini, so no need to go every week to a store on the other side of town. The green used for the salad can be whatever you have at hand and can be eaten raw - any variety of lettuce, watercress, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Valerianella&quot;&gt;Valerianella&lt;/a&gt;, or a mix of all of these will do. The first time I have seen Valerianella was in Germany, so I am not sure about the availability in other countries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I noticed that depending on the brand, tahini can be more or less fatty and I was suspicious that some of it might be of lower quality. So, I asked a colleague that has a middle eastern background if there was any way to choose “the best” tahini and apparently having a layer of fat at the top of the jar is normal and expected. Unless it is too much, let’s say 1/4 of the volume, it actually indicates a good quality tahini. One thing to bear in mind is one should homogenize the tahini - for instance with a spoon - before taking it from the jar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for the halloumi, don’t fret if you can’t find “real” halloumi - any grill cheese with do, and I tend to buy the cheap ones pre-marinated with chili. And if you don’t have it or are not that hungry, no problem, the salad will work without it as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whilst you could use black pepper to season this dish, I strongly recommend white pepper which goes extremely well with some fish dishes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;source&quot;&gt;Source&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inspiration from a &lt;a href=&quot;http://stupideasypaleo.com/2015/01/30/paleo-lemon-tahini-tuna-salad-recipe/&quot;&gt;paleo website&lt;/a&gt;, modified to include some extra  ingredients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Servings: 2&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Prep Time:  20 mins&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cook Time:  10 mins&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Total Time:  30 mins&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tuna: 140g, canned in water&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tahini: 2 tablespoons&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Salad greens: 2-3 cups, for instance half a lettuce.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cherry tomatoes: a handful&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;lemon juice: 2-3 tablespoons, or 1 lemon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Garlic: 1 clove, pressed&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;White pepper: 1 teaspoon, or to taste&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sea salt: to taste&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Olive oil: 2 tablespoons&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wash the salad and the tomatoes. Shred the salad and halve or quarter the tomatoes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lay the salad on large plates, dot with the tomatoes, drizzle the olive oil, and add a bit of salt.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Brush slightly the halloumi with olive oil and grill it in a grill pan with medium heat.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;While the halloumi is grilling, take a bowl and mix the tahini, lemon juice, garlic, tuna (without the water), and white pepper. If the mixture is too thick add some drops of water, but remember it should have the consistency of a paste. Spoon it into the middle of the plates.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Finish off by cutting the grilled halloumi in small pieces and dotting the salad with it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;


    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/blog/Tahini-and-tuna-salad/&quot;&gt;Tahini and tuna salad&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by António Domingues at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on September 15, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Feta cheesecake]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/blog/Feta-cheesecake/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/blog/Feta-cheesecake</id>
  <published>2016-09-09T17:00:02+02:00</published>
  <updated>2016-09-09T17:00:02+02:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>António Domingues</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>amjdomingues@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;I follow the food articles on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/&quot;&gt;The Guardian&lt;/a&gt; in search of inspiration for when I need something different. Most of the times the recipes are not People-friendly and require way too many odd (expensive) ingredients or are a full time job. There however times when something hits the sweet spot (pun intended) and this &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2016/sep/03/feta-cheese-cheesecake-filo-frittata-recipe-swap&quot;&gt;cheesecake with Feta&lt;/a&gt; is a case in point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For this recipe I had to do very few minor changes, mostly due to the fact that I don’t own a 20 cm cake form, but rather a 25 cm, so the ingredients for the filling were scaled up by a 1/3, with one exception: sugar. The original recipe is quite generous with the sugar, 160g, whereas half of that is enough for me. My recommendation is that, if following the original recipe, you start with half of the sugar, and taste the filling adjusting if needed, before adding it to the crust.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another change, this time by complete accident but turned out to add even more flavor, was that I added the lemon juice to the filling by accident - it should have been only the zest. This mistake paid off though. Also, I did not have black sesame seeds (who does?) so I used normal sesame seeds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since the amount of filling was increased in my version, time in the oven was also extended by about 5-10 minutes. Check the cake after 40 minutes and  if not slightly brown on the top, extend the time as needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;things-to-try&quot;&gt;Things to try&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;replace sugar with honey&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;replace digestive biscuits crust with an almond flour based one&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/images/img/FetaCheesecake.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A lovely dessert can be prepared in a few minutes.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;source&quot;&gt;Source&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All credits go to &lt;a href=&quot;https://witness.theguardian.com/user/borrowedbread&quot;&gt;Faye Cooke&lt;/a&gt; and The Guardian.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So here are my changes to the recipe, though if you stick to the original you won’t go wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Servings: 8-10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Prep Time:  30 mins&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cooking Time:  45 mins&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Total Time:  75 mins&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Digestive biscuits: 150g, crushed&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Salt: a pinch&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sesame seeds: 1 1/2 tablespoon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Butter: 50 grams, melted&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Feta: 300 grams&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cream cheese: 400 grams&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Eggs: 3&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Zest of 1 lemon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Caster sugar: 80 grams&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Peaches: 2&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Raspberries: 100 grams, frozen&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lemon juice: 2 tablespoons&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Honey: 1 tablespoons&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Unsalted butter: 20g&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Thyme: 1 sprig, leaves picked&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Line a 20cm springform cake tin with greaseproof paper. Put the biscuit crumbs into a bowl with the salt and sesame seeds and mix in the melted butter until well combined. Press the mixture into the bottom of the cake tin, evening out with the back of a spoon, and put in the fridge while you prepare the filling.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Preheat the oven to 180C/350F/gas mark 4. In a mixing bowl, break down the feta using a fork. Whisk in the cream cheese, eggs, lemon zest, one tablespoon of lemon juice and the sugar. Put the tin on a baking sheet, pour the filling on to the crust and give it a tap to even it out. Bake in the middle of the oven for 40 minutes, or until almost set.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Meanwhile, dice the peaches and put the pieces in a roasting tray with the raspberries, lemon juice and the honey. Flake over the unsalted butter, cover with foil and set aside. When the cheesecake has 15 minutes left, put the roasting tin on the bottom shelf of the oven.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Remove the cheesecake and fruit from the oven. Let them cool slightly. Carefully transfer the cheesecake to a plate. Lift the fruit from its juice and spoon on top of the cheesecake. Pour over 1 tbsp the juice, then chill the rest.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Scatter over the thyme leaves. Serve with the reserved juice from the fruits.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;


    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/blog/Feta-cheesecake/&quot;&gt;Feta cheesecake&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by António Domingues at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on September 09, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>

</feed>